Grüezi youtubers here is the guy with the
Swiss accent with a new episode around
sensors and microcontrollers a new
mailbag all hand checked in Switzerland
it means that it's free of charge our
limitation for the customs is about 60
Swiss francs is a free of duty and free
of we 80 and usually these packages
anyway are declared only five dollars or
so or even a gift so let's start I have
some of them already prepared so I don't
need my Swiss Army knife too much today
these are very nice power supplies 3.3
volt 3 watt and the input is 100 to 240
volt AC and 3 watt means 1 ampere these
are well suited for most of the small
gadgets and this one is 5 volt also 3
watt a little bit less than 1 ampere but
still ok for many many applications and
they are very nicely done so you have a
clear separation between high voltage
and low voltage if you solder it on a
PCB you can clearly separate the
dangerous zone from the not dangerous
zone so I quickly want to test out the
quality of these power supplies and
people who watch my mailbox know that I
got a insulation tester in one of my
last videos and I want to use this now
to check out if the insulation between
the primary and the secondary is
hi enough and because this is the first
time I use this device I just want to
check it out quickly to do that I use
just an ordinary multimeter and I
connect the two wires like that and now
I connected it to these two blocks here
and I selected now 250 volt what I
expect is that we will get 250 volt
across this and we will see the
resistance of this multimeter shown here
in the display so I press the button
test and we see 250 volt exactly and
here exactly 10 mega ohm so this
multimeter is capable to deal with 250
volt it's even should be able to deal
with 1000 volts but I will not do that I
will stop at 500 volt and usually these
kind of multimeters have any input
resistance of about 10 mega ohm so I
think it's quite spot-on
the only issue is that I get minus 250
volt which is somehow strange and these
two probably I have to check maybe yeah
I know why this is earth and this is
life e and L you see it here so RTFM
read the fucking manual anyway now it
should be okay 250 volt and we have the
250 volt 500 volt
we have the 497 volt which is very
accurate and 9.9 mega ohm resistance
perfect and now I try to kill this
device here and to do so I put one wire
to the secondary and one wire to the
primary so I hope so I hope you can see
it now so now what I do is I apply 250
volt across the whole power supply this
simulates the worst case that the 220
volt or 110 volt or whatever you have on
the primary that it comes through to the
secondary and kills all our circuits now
I expect very high resistance here
between primary and secondary it should
be extremely high and this is also why I
choose not make home but geek ohm and I
start with 250 volt and now maybe I kill
this power supply
no it's wife's indefinite very high
resistance so with 500 volt do the same
thing again very high resistance so
there is no danger in this configuration
of course I have to do all the other
configurations also but then I'm sure
that this device is completely isolated
from the primary to the secondary this
next one
these are five millimeter by five
millimeter or fifty-fifty and these are
35 by 35 so they are smaller but the
same principle and I learned from
Charles lore that these should have
really nice-looking yellow yellow color
very special ones by the way
Joel's lure is a very good channel and
you find it in my favourites
unfortunately I discovered that there
are many different SK 68 12 neopixels
and it was not sufficient to just order
a bunch of them the ones I thought were
just normal neopixels like the ws2812 B
with only three channels red green and
blue you get however these neopixels
with four channels but also not the ones
Charles mentioned they are RGB and warm
or cold white so I went back to Charles
video and discovered a link where he
sells these special RGB yellow neopixels
they are now in the mail by the way you
also need a different library to drive
these parts link is in the description
the next one is already opened because I
had to confirm delivery
few things I think from banggood two
very ordinary Arduino clones because I
have a young guy helping me out
sometimes and I need it just an ordinary
Arduino to give it to him that he can
start his hobby a little bit so normal
thing and I ordered three of them they
are dirt cheap I don't remember how much
and for him I also ordered a housing for
the Arduino and acrylic housing so it
will have a nice a nice look I peeled
now all the protection off which is
quite a work and that even got a nice
manual with it so I think I will be able
to put it together it says you have to
start with board two and board one but
you have many possibilities to put it
together so you have to pay attention
the Arduino 's have here two holes which
are closer than here and you see also
the holes here and then you know exactly
how you have to position it that is the
trick if you get this done then the race
will follow
so hours later no not really but it's a
it's a not easy to to put all these
small screws in but now it's nicely
looking and I still have this one which
is spare somehow but it's nice he will
like it I think and this was also in the
same package
and this is something quite important
this is to clean the soldering iron and
there are two different sorts to be
bought one are of steel and one is brass
personally I do not like it all the
steel one the steel wool this is also I
think quite a cheap thing and I like
much more this brass one and it has to
be replaced from time to time because
the solder really sticks into it and I
have it here so I can clean my soldering
iron it's always important that you have
it on your desk somewhere so pay
attention that you get the brass one and
not the steel one and this is a gadget
quite an interesting principle you write
something here or you draw something and
then if you want to raise it you have
here the areason button so like that you
write something I hope you see it and
then press the button and it's a way I'm
not sure how this works it does not look
like it has a battery or at least it is
no replaceable battery but it's a nice
thing if you can note for example an IP
address of your ESPE or something like
that or at least you want to do today
and then at the evening if you did it
you just use it and the pen is here next
one
this is for my solar project maybe I
ordered a few charging units and this
one is charging unit and here you can
put the 18 650 battery and then you can
charge it here with 5 volts or more and
here you can discharge it or vice versa
maybe I can use this for my solar
controller because obviously should have
also a protection and everything for it
for the lipo battery here this is a part
of a normal power bank for the next one
I do not need my knife because I already
opened it to have a look and this is a
lot of stuff here oh this is not very
well packaged one of them is open
obviously so normal Remus
another way is MOS and I think it should
be 1/3 1/3 we must just to start to
stock up my we MOS boards and these are
original we mas here with the most sign
or at least I hope they are originally
Mo's but now there are more interesting
things here we have a new ESP 32 board
and this one has also lipo charging and
everything and you should be able to
connect the lipo battery here and this
one is another ESP 32 port this one does
not have the lipo charging thing and the
in a third one also an ESP 32 but like
the we Mo's very small but I think it's
a slightly different format and by the
way it has two buttons here the next one
here is also an ESP 32 but this is a
rolling board and it has also a lipo
support it seems to be from Windows but
I'm not sure but anyway it's important
that it is an ESP 32 and you know now
what the plan is I think I will do an
overview about the newest boards in the
ESP 32 area and this is the last one in
this package and this seems to be a
quite interesting one because this one
has an O LED display right on the board
it had does not have too many pins this
is this might be a problem in some
projects but if you want to do some data
locking or stuff like that that seems to
be an interesting board that is why it
has also the Wii mote sign on it I'm
really not sure so we have now plenty of
ESP 32 stuff to start with an overview
about the new boards and these are also
interesting boards they are the same
these are signal generators ad
9850 and they can produce a variable
frequency
is and I used one of these in my hack of
the garage door opener and I want to
produce an additional opener to be put
in my car I nearly forgot this one this
is an mp3 player and with an SD card and
I might use this to give one of my
devices a voice output next one in
stuff here and if we open this one first
[Applause]
this is an other ESP 32 board obviously
also from Remus and this has a 86 18 650
battery which can be put in here and it
has quite a lot of pins here and of
course it needs an on/off switch if you
have a battery here and it seems also to
have a charger here with this inductive
'ti and and serial to USB converter very
nice port is also part of the review
next one this is a arduino shield but it
has a esp8266 on board and it is a ESP
13 shield from do it and the purpose of
this shield seems to be that you can
Wi-Fi enable a arduino a normal arduino
board and i just wanted to try if this
work because sometimes you need more
than a few pins and then the Arduino arm
operator or also if you need more than
only one ADC then it's also good to use
an Arduino but quite often these days I
want to have a connectivity and so this
is probably a good compromise I think
this one belongs also to the last one it
has it is a shield to the ESP 32 we had
before it has also these pins here and
it is called ex shield so the format is
called
ex it's not the we Mo's the we MOS is
small is
over here is not as wide as SDX
but we will see I think I should get
also the ground plane for these and here
we have another X shield
I think yep so you see this is a proto
board but it has the same size it's the
same idea of the way most shields you
can stack them the next one is already
opened it is extensions for Raspberry Pi
GPIO pins for the header so I can
connect this to the raspberry and then I
can connect this to my project board the
next one also is already open it's also
from banggood
it is a electrical parameter tester and
what it really is
it measures vault and ampere and also
calculates the power because I do some
experiments with solar panels I think
this can be nice addition to my
electronic load of course it comes with
a description and the description is
also in English I print it now a nice
box put in a 9-volt battery it should
run about 50 hours with this with this
battery here and switch I can switch it
on here and now you see and now you see
Walt ampere and so on input output
voltage sense I will explain why we need
this voltage sense in my video about
electronic loads so let's just check it
out I connect five volts to the input
and the small electronic USB load to the
output and now we already see the 1
ampere flowing and the voltage sends to
the input for example here we have 4
point 9 5 volt 1 amp ere for what two
minutes operation it's 30 degrees maybe
inside the cut the housing outside it's
a little bit less and it counts here
ampere iris and what iris and I can
reset these waters and ampere hours if I
press the small button
now it's zero this is a very nice device
here and it's absolutely worth the money
will be very handy in my solar panel
test next one this is a B and O 0:55
chip from Bosch and this is one of the
newer acceleration sensors and it
obviously has also already a
microprocessor on the chip and it should
be much easier to read the annals and
all the stuff from this one you do not
have to deal with quad tear neons or
whatever to get your self balancing
robot or whatever I hope I can use this
one here for a new version of my self
balancing robot this is the old version
here with which has a quadcopter board
here and for communication it has an n
RF 24:01 and I would like to build or to
rebuild one of these but with an ESP and
with this sensor here and with blink as
a remote control we will see next one is
also already open I was not able to
resist to open this one they do not look
like spectacular but I think they are
spectacular and I will show you why
these are in one hand LEDs and on the
other hand they are touch sensors very
nice new sort of devices in different
colors these two here come from banggood
and the bank
it now every time I order something I
get these stickers here I have no clue
where I should stick them on but anyway
this is the more important thing these
are two sorts of microphones USB
microphones for my Raspberry Pi because
I want also to start to experiment with
voice on the Raspberry Pi next one I
think I know what this is this is the
awaited face for these X shields you see
here you can put here one of the board's
we saw before like that I think it has
to do with this one because it looks
like it fits at least from a only
mechanical point of view and it fits
also somehow with these ports here and
with the ESP 32 and also with this
prototype port but I think I do not
understand completely how it works but
maybe I figure it out till I make my
video about the different boards here
and by the way I just discovered that
they solved the issue I had with the
shield with the way most shield you have
switches here you can select on which
pin you want to have your pixels here I
think that is a good idea because with
the way most shields it was fixed next
one
again works for my Renu here another
port with a battery compartment and an
esp8266 so this is a similar concept
that this one but this is with the 32
and this is where the 82 66 here we have
all the pins for the ESP and here we
have much more pins for the ESP 32 and
this one here has also a battery but it
this is only charging so this is just
the power supply and the last one in
this package is again an X port also
with this nice looking dip switch here
and a buzzer just about it and it's
called X buzzer next one towards
our gesture sensors and they seem to
have two holes here one is I think LED
sender and the other one is a receiver
and they should be able to detect some
gestures we will see I do not have any
plans for them it's just I thought this
is an interesting board and maybe I just
play around a little bit
finally we reached the end of this huge
mailbag
it was probably the longest episode of
this channel please comment if you were
hard enough and persevered till here I
hope this episode was useful or at least
interesting for you if true then like
bye